Praveen Kumar (1) Featured

Associate seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis,

Log4j,HTML,Java,Javascript,JPA,JQuery,JSP Servlets,Hibernate,Jasper Reports, Spring



Current Designation: Associate-Projects, IT Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 6 Month(s) Current Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Associate, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Log4j, HTML, Java, Javascript, JPA, JQuery, JSP

Servlets, Hibernate, Jasper Reports, Spring

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Having 3.6 Years of relevant IT experience in developing and maintaining Client/server, Web based Applications Using JAVA J2SE (Core Java), J2EE technologies and Java frameworks.

Proficient in programming using Core Java, J2EE and Java Framework (Spring, Hibernate).

Strong Experience in Core Java technologies, Collection, Multithreading and Object Oriented Programming concepts. Strong knowledge and working experience in Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring REST and Spring Data JPA. Good hands of experience in Design Patterns like Model View Controller (MVC), Data Access Object (DAO), Singleton, Strategy Design Pattern, Factory Design Pattern and Cache Design Pattern.

Having hands of experience in REST Web services.

Having hands of experience in writing client side component using HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript and Ajax. Having hands of experience in writing junit test cases TDD (Test Driven Development) using JUnit and Mockito.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions India Ltd as Associate-Projects, IT Dec 2018 to Till Date

DASH (Distribution and Sales Hub)

Role Software Developer Duration Jan 2019 to till date

Environment

Tech/Languages: Java 1.8, Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, Micro Services, Angular Js.

Database: Oracle

Server: Apache Tomcat, AWS

Project description:

DASH is an international theatrical release planning system for motion picture. It is used by Warner Bros. executives and other users in the "Home Office" and by users in various territories around the world that may or may not be WB employees. It tracks Release dates, Revenue estimates, Advertising and publicity estimates, Estimates for number of prints and prints costs, Box Office grosses, Ultimate (expected gross over the life of the picture, estimated at various points in the life cycle). It is not a financial system. It is used to gather data and plan release. Typical planning involves choosing release dates, how much to spend on advertising and publicity, how many prints to make, how much the film is

1/22/2021

expected to gross etc. Information is gathered ad evaluated in real time. For instance, if a film does poorly in its first releases, budgets for ad pub and prints may be reduced for future releases of the same picture in other territories.

Responsibilities:

Analyzing the design document, system requirements. Implemented Action Classes. Implemented Business logic. Developed DAO class for DB interaction. Developed Rest end points. Written TDD and BDD. Involved in bug fixing.

Vara United Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer

Jul 2017 to Dec 2018

LAM (Logical Access Management)

Client ICICI Bank Software Engineer Role Duration Jun 2017 to Dec 2018 Environment

Tech/Languages: Java, JSP, Spring

Database: Oracle.

Web Server: Web logic 12.3

Project description:

LAM (Logical Access Management) is an application developed to cater to the process of logical access maintenance activity for various applications. The activities can be classified into viz; Creation/Modification/Deletion/Unlock/Reset. On submission of a request in LAM, the request flows to appropriate approvers. The request is approved or rejected by the Approver online. An approved request will flow to concerned logical access team who act on these requests. Once action is taken on the approved request, the call is closed and necessary information is conveyed through auto-generated mails sent from a common email id Application Logical Access Team.

Responsibilities:

Implemented Spring Handler Classes. Developed Spring DAO. Designed JSP's as per the requirement. Used LDAP authentication. Mail Configuration.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Magadh University, Bihar in 2012

PG: MCA (Computers) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, Bhopal in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
JAVA Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8	
Html, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Ajax	
Oracle 10g, MySQL 5.0 JDBC	
Servlet, JSP Spring 3.X Hibernate 3.X	
JPA	
Tomcat, Web logic Log 4J	
JASPER REPORTS	
RESTful Web Services	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time